[ Background Conversations ]
谈话声
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Good afternoon, everyone.
&gt;&gt; 大家下午好
And welcome to Metal 2
欢迎来到
Optimization and Debugging.
Metal 2 优化和调试
As you know, we're talking a lot
你们已经知道 我们今年
about Metal 2 this year, with
有很多关于 Metal 2 的内容
some great new enhancements to
在一些平台上实现了
the platform including GP driven
一些很好的提升
rendering, machine learning
包括 GP 驱动渲染 机器学习加速
acceleration, and a macOS VR,
macOS VR 和
and external GPU support.
外部 GPU 支持
And not forgetting Advanced
别忘了还有
Optimization Tools.
高级优化工具
So, this afternoon, we're going
所以 今天下午我们
to talk about the current Metal
将会讨论一下当前的
tools, give you a recap of
Metal 工具
those, talk about some great new
简要概括一下它们
enhancements to the Metal frame
并介绍一些很棒的
debugger, and then finally cover
针对 Metal 帧调试工具的提升
some major enhancements in terms
最后讨论一些
of GPU profiling.
关于 GPU 配置的内容
But first, the frame debugger.
首先 我们来看看 帧调试工具
So hopefully you're all familiar
我希望你们都
with this tool.
熟悉这个工具
It is our fully-featured frame
帧调试工具集成在 Xcode 中
debugger integrated into Xcode,
功能齐全
that lets you capture your Metal
让你可以处理你的
2 work, be it computer graphics,
Metal 2 作品
and then step through it into
让它成为计算机图形
the debugger, to inspect state
并且可以进一步检查
and resources, letting you debug
状态和资源
and optimize.
让你能够调试和优化
One of our focuses this year has
提升帧调试
been on improving the
工具的性能
performance to the frame
是我们最近几年
debugger, and in particular, we
的工作中心之一
paid particular regard to
我们尤其
improving the speed with which
注意提升
captures happen.
捕获速度
And I'm happy to say that
我很开心告诉大家
compared to Xcode 8, Xcode 9 now
与 Xcode 8 相比
captures up to 10 times as fast,
Xcode 9 现在的捕获速度
getting you from clicking the
可以达到原来的 10 倍
Capture button to into the
让你从点按 Capture 按钮
debugger much, much more
到打开调试工具的时间
quickly.
大大缩短
As you'd expect, we have full
如你期待的那样
support for all the new Metal 2
我们全面支持了 Metal 2 的 API
API, including Raster order
包括光栅顺序组
groups, sampler arrays, viewport
采样数组  Viewport 数组
arrays, and the new pixel and
以及全新的像素和
vertex array formats.
顶点数组格式
One particular part of Metal 2
在 Metal 2 中
that we've paid a lot of
我们花了很大精力
attention to is the support for
来支持全新的
the new argument buffers.
参数缓冲器
With this, in the buffer viewer,
有了它 在缓冲查看器中
you can now see all the
你可以看到所有的
argument, buffer arguments,
参数 缓冲参数
displayed in line, and you can
都一行行显示出来
click through whether it be to
你可以点按它们选择是否要
attach your sampler, buffer, or
附上你的采样器 缓冲器
another argument buffer itself.
或者其他参数缓冲器
We've also added support for VR
此外 随着对 SteamVR 的自动支持
captures this year, with
我们今年开始支持
automatic support for SteamVR.
VR 捕获
And we've added support for you
我们也为你们提供了
to view your submitted surfaces
让你们可以以立体的形式
in stereo.
查看你们上传的界面的支持
So when you get to the Submit
当你们发送 提交
call, you're sending your
指令的时候 你将会向
surfaces to the VR compositer,
VR 混合器发送你的界面
you will see left eye and right
你会同时看到
eye alongside each other, to
左右眼的视图
quickly spot any discrepancies.
可以帮助你发现其中的差异
Another area of focus this year
今年的另一个工作重心是
has been on improving the
为了要针对更复杂的计算任务
workflow for capturing more
进行捕获
complex workloads.
我们改进了捕获工作流
So now if you're doing
所以如果你现在
compute-only work in Metal, or
只在 Metal 里做纯计算任务
perhaps you're using multiple
或者如果你同时有多个
Metal cues, it's much easier to
Metal 命令队列  现在我们就可以
capture exactly the work that
更轻松地  准确捕获到你想要
you want.
的那部分内容
We've added the lightweight
我们还添加了轻便型
capture API, with some new Metal
捕获 API  其中内置了一些新的 Metal
capture scope objects, that you
捕获作用域对象  我们可以在新建
create at startup and then reuse
项目时创建这些对象  然后后期在
every frame to surround the work
每一帧都可以重复利用  可以用来
that you want to capture.
包裹住之后想捕获的部分
You'll see a demo of this later,
我们稍后会看到这项的演示
but it's great for being able to
这给我们带来了新的可能性
say, group all your regular
比如说  现在可以把我们所有的
rendering work in one scope, and
正常渲染任务都包在一个作用域里
some asynchronous work like
把其他那些异步任务  比如说
regenerating your tessellation
重新生成我们的密铺因子缓冲区
factor buffers, in another
这一类的任务  归到另一个
scope, and when you come to
作用域里  这样等我们开始捕获的时候
capture, you get exactly what
就可以精准地制定区域  获得想要的
you want.
结果
We also have support for
我们现在还支持
triggering captures
在我们的应用程序中
programmatically from your app.
用编程方式触发捕获过程
We use this a lot within our
其实我们在自己的测试应用程序里
test apps ourselves, so that we
也经常使用这一功能  用上之后
can quickly do a gesture on the
比如我们可以立马在设备上做一个
device, and trigger a frame
什么手势  然后就可以自动触发
capture, without having to
帧捕获  我们就不用再
switch our focus back to Xcode.
费力切换回 Xcode 去实现这个功能了
Another new feature this year is
今年要宣布的另一个新功能
support for Xcode's Quick Looks
是 Xcode 的快速预览(Quick Looks)
support.
功能
So now, you have lightweight
现在在 CPU 调试工具里
Metal debugging in the CPU
有了新的轻便型 Metal
debugger.
调试功能
So if you hit a breakpoint, and
假设我们现在再遇到断点
there is a Metal texture there,
如果包含有 Metal 纹理
we'll pull back the data from
快速预览就会从 GPU 里
the metal texture on the GPU and
自动提取 Metal 纹理数据
let you view it there and then.
然后给大家提供实时预览
Similarly, with buffers and
同样的功能  也支持预览缓冲区
samplers.
和采样器
This is great for those cases
对于有些不太方便
where a full frame capture might
做完整帧捕获的项目  这个功能
be too invasive, for instance,
非常有用  举个例子来说
if you're debugging your
如果我们要调试的是
resource loading or some of the
资源载入  或者一些设置代码
setup code.
这一类
It is also great in cases where
另外  如果我们要调试一些
you're debugging some compute
计算任务  用这个断点预览
workloads as well.
也会非常方便
So last year we introduced
去年我们介绍了
support for rich filtering
在帧调试工具里
throughout the frame debugger,
全局可用的  丰富的过滤功能
so that you could filter both on
我们可以同时过滤
things like resource properties,
比如  资源属性  这一类东西
but also within the frame
但同时  在帧
navigator, you can filter based
导航栏里  我们也可以依据
on contextual data, so what
上下文数据进行过滤  这样如果
resources you're using at a
我们的过滤条件是一个特定绘制指令
given draw call will let that
所用的资源  过滤结果就会输出
draw call show up.
那个特定的绘制指令
Well we've taken this to the
我们今年把这一功能进行了改进
next level this year, with
能达到的功能更上一层楼了
support for data mining
现在我们还可以支持在整个
throughout your capture tray.
捕获帧内进行数据挖掘
So now, when you type, we'll
所以现在我们一边输入  程序
give you context aware, or
就会一边自动返回上下文相关的
complete suggestions.
自动补全建议
And we now allow compound terms.
而且我们现在还支持复合术语
So now if you search for a given
所以如果现在先限定某个特定的
encoder, and then you search for
编码器  然后再限定某个
a texture, we'll only show you
纹理  我们现在给你显示
auto-complete suggestions for
出的的自动补全建议  就会是
the textures that are actually
那个特定编码器里
used within that encoder.
实际用到的纹理
One of our most requested
这几年来  我们收到
features over the years has been
请求最多的一项功能就是
support for pixel inspection.
像素审查 (Pixel Inspection) 功能
And we've finally caught up with
我们现在终于满足了这一需求
So now you can do detailed
所以现在我们可以针对
inspection of individual pixels
每一个独立像素  做详细的审查
within your textures and your
不管是在纹理  还是
render targets.
在渲染目标中
And if you have multiple
而如果你的渲染
attachments to your render
目标中  包含有多个附件
targets, we'll show you the
我们还会在同一时间
pixel values for the same
给你显示出每个
location in each attachment at
附件内部同等位置处的
the same time.
像素值
So it's really good if you're
所以如果我们要看着附件调试
trying to debug what the color
颜色值啊  同时还要调试
value is alongside that and
模版啊之类的东西
stencil and such like.
就会非常方便
It's also very valuable for
这个功能在调试计算任务
debugging compute workloads if
的时候  也非常有用
you're working with images there
比如你正在处理图片
and you are, for instance,
假设我们的
halfway through your CNN and you
CNN 正做到一半  但是想测试一下
want to test watch to see what
看看各个缓冲区里面的实际
the exact values in the buffers
数值都是多少  就可以用这个来
are.
审查
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Another new feature we
我们去年介绍的
introduced last year was our
另一个新功能  就是
vertex attribute viewer, where
顶点属性观察器  在这里
you can see all the vertex data
我们可以看到  所有在传入我们的
as it goes into your vertex
顶点着色引擎的顶点数据
shader, you know, shown on a per
数据按照每个顶点分开
vertex basis.
显示
Well, this year, we've added
好了  今年  我们又添加
support for viewing the outputs
了新的功能  现在我们也可以看到
from your vertex shader as well,
顶点着色引擎输出的顶点数据了
and we will display this inline
我们还会把这个内联
with all the other input data,
和之前支持的输入时的数据并列显示
so in this case, you can see
所以在这个例子里  我们可以看到
your position inputs, and your
输入的顶点位置数据  和输出的
position outputs, at the same
顶点位置数据  同时显示在
time.
一起
Well, to show you all these
好了  现在该给大家实际
great new features in action,
演示一下我说过的这些新功能了
I'd like to invite my colleague,
请允许我邀请我的同事
Max, to the stage, who is going
Max 上台  他将会给大家
to give you a demo of all this
演示刚刚说过的这些精彩的
new stuff.
新功能
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Hello. Great to see you here
大家好  很高兴今天在这里见到
today.
大家
I hope you are doing fine and
我希望大家手头工作进展都不错
you are as hyped about Metal as
而你们都和我们一样  对 Metal 充满
we are.
激情
Xcode GPU debugger helps you
Xcode 的 GPU 调试工具可以帮我们
debugging your GPU and the Metal
调试我们的 GPU 和 Metal 占用
usage.
情况
I am Max, and I am going to
我叫作 Max  今天我会帮大家
maximize your debugging
最优化 (maximize) 你们的调试
experience, showing our new
体验  给大家演示下新的
features.
功能
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Yeah, let me run my demo app.
让我运行一下我的示例程序
It is rendering a beautiful
这里渲染出来的  是一幅美丽的
scenery, reflects snowy
风景  显示出来  雪中
mountains, grass that is waving
的山脉啦  在风中飘动
in the wind, and to make it even
的草啦  然后为了让效果
look nicer, I added some
看起来更好  我还添加了一些
particles that are glowing in
颗粒  并让它们在空中闪闪
the air.
发光
But as you can see, the
但就像大家看到的那样
particles of the grass, there is
草上面的这些颗粒  看起来
some kind of a problem.
渲染得有点问题
So let's figure this out.
所以让我们看看怎么解决一下
As a first step, let's check if
作为调试的第一步  让我们先看看
the texture is correct.
纹理设置对了没有
Let me set a breakpoint in the
我们在渲染循环里设置
rendering loop, where this
一个断点  设置在正要
texture is being used.
使用这个纹理的时候
Hovering over a variable gives
把鼠标悬停在一个变量上
you access to Xcode's data tips,
我们就可以看到 Xcode 的数据提示
and you can quick look into the
可通过 Xcode 这个提示快速查看该变量的
texture data.
纹理数据
This data is fetched live from
这个纹理数据  是实时从 GPU
the GPU, and it helps you to
抓取的  可以帮助我们
verify the resources you are
快速确认  是否绑定上了正确
binding, and, of course, it
的资源  当然  这个功能对于
works with all Metal resources.
所有的 Metal 资源都可用
The texture in this case looks
我们目前这个变量的纹理看起来
correct.
没有错
So what else can we check?
那么我们还有什么可以检查的
Our next step is to capture a
我们下一步  就可以开始捕获帧
frame.
了
Using the little camera icon in
只需点击调试栏里的这个
the debug bar, let's you capture
小照相机图标  我们就可以捕获
a frame, but using a long press
一帧  但如果我们长按这个图标
gives you access to capture
就会显示出菜单  可以选择捕获
scopes and command cues.
作用域  或者命令队列
A capture scope is one path
捕获作用域是通过渲染通道
through your rendering pipeline.
完成
Like my environment map, I'm
就像我的环境图  这个
only updating every couple of
我每几帧  才更新
frames.
一次
In this case, however, we want
但这个例子里  我们想要
to capture rendering, this is
捕获的是渲染过程  因为这个
where the particles are being
过程里才会真正开始绘制颗粒
So let's capture this.
所以我们点击  捕获一下
And already done.
这就捕获好了
For those who are not familiar
对于那些不太熟悉我们的工具
with our tool, I will give you a
界面的人  我先给大家
quick run through of all the
快速讲解一下在这个
views you are seeing here.
界面上  都有些什么东西
On the left side, we have the
在界面左侧  我们可以看到
debug navigator.
调试工具导航栏
It is in [inaudible]
在这里按等级
presentation of your frame, and
显示了我们的帧  为了更加
to help you, we automatically
方便大家调试使用  自动
group by command buffers and
进行了分组  分开了命令缓冲区
command encoders.
和命令编码器
But also your debugging groups
我们的调试组
are shown here, giving you fine
也显示在这里了  让我们在
grain control over the grouping.
微小的层面上也可以掌控调整帧
You can select the draw call or
我们可以选择绘制指令
any other Metal call to inspect
或者任何其他的 Metal 指令  来审查
further details.
其更多细节
The editor in the center is
位于界面中央的编辑器
showing the bound resources.
向我们展示了绑定的资源
All the Metal objects you are
展示了选中的 API 指令中
using in the selected API call.
我们所用到的所有的 Metal 对象
Again, you can see labeling your
在这里我们也可以看到  为我们的对象
objects will greatly increase
添加标签  可以有效提高调试时的
readability.
可读性
So I suggest to do that.
我建议大家都养成这个习惯
The editor on the right side is
界面右侧的编辑器
showing the attachments, the
显示的是附件  是最近
output of the last issued draw
一次绘制指令的输出结果
So whenever you are, like,
所以不管你什么时候
navigating through your frame,
不管在帧的哪里
you instantly see where you are.
都可以马上看到自己在哪一步
On the bottom, we have our
在界面最下方  我们有
variables view, where you can
变量观察器  可以让我们
access all the states of each
方便地查看每个 Metal 对象的
Metal object.
状态
Back to our problem with the
好了  我们回到刚刚颗粒的
particles.
问题上
Here, we can make use of our new
现在我们就可以试验一下超强的
super powerful filtering.
过滤功能
So I know the particles are
好了  现在我知道  那些颗粒
drawn somewhere in my forward
是在正向渲染过程中某处绘制的
So let me filter for this.
所以让我们试着过滤一下
Filtering for command encoder
如果对命令编码器进行过滤
will only show API calls inside
那么结果只会显示这个命令编码器
this command encoder.
里的 API 指令
Like this.
比如像这样
But it is still a lot.
但结果还是太多了
So let me add an additional
所以我们再添加一个额外的过滤
filter.
条件
We know it is using our particle
我们知道会用到颗粒
texture.
纹理
Filtering for texture will only
如果对纹理进行过滤  那么结果
show draw calls using this
只会显示使用了此纹理的绘制
texture.
指令
And boom, this combination of
这就好了  这两个过滤条件
filters results in a single API
叠加  就能过滤出唯一的 API 指令
call we want to inspect further.
而这一指令正是我们希望进一步研究的
So let's go here.
我们来看一下
Let's take a look at the bound
我们先看一下这个指令绑定的
resources.
资源
The vertex attributes combines
这里  顶点属性中包含了
the data that is going into your
输入顶点函数的数据  也包含了
vertex function and leaving it.
离开顶点函数的数据
Maybe we are doing something
也许我们就是在这里搞错了
wrong with our geometry here, so
一些几何特征的设定
let's open this by double
所以我们看一下  双击
clicking.
打开
Let me also hide the attachments
让我们先把这边的附件
for a moment.
隐藏一下
Last year, we started to show
去年  我们给大家展示了
you a nice layout for all the
缓冲区一种更好的布局
And this year we added something
今年我们还新添加了一些别的东西
In the header, you can see the
在界面眉头  我们可以看到
direction where the data is
下方显示的数据是输入还是
flowing.
输出
And if we take a look, this is
如果我们看一下  这边
the output data, the data that
就是输出的数据  是离开
is leaving the vertex function.
顶点函数的数据
This is the output position of
这些显示了全部颗粒顶点
every particle vertex, and as we
输出时的位置  我们在这里
can see here, there is no
可以看到  没有
obvious error, like big numbers
什么很明显的错误  比如哪个数据
or something like this, so I
数值过大之类的问题  所以我先
assume this data is correct.
假设这些数据都是正确的
So what else can we check?
那么我们还可以检查哪里
The debug navigator now gives
调试工具导航栏现在还可以让
you quick access to all the
我们快速定位并进入到当前
views related to this draw call.
绘制指令所相关的所有视图
Let's switch back to the
让我们再切换回
attachments again.
附件看看
We are using two render targets
我们现在显示了
here.
两种渲染目标
Color, and depth.
颜色  和深度
Let's inspect some more pixel
让我们再审查一些
values.
像素值吧
Using the inspect pixels button
我们可以使用位于界面右下方的
in the lower right corner, we
审查像素按钮  这就可以
will present a new tool.
唤出一个新工具
A loop. This loop displays the
一个环形  这个圆环里显示的
value like they are outputted by
数据  和片元函数输出的
the fragment function.
数据完全一致
And you can move the loop around
我们可以用鼠标在渲染目标上
all the render targets.
随意移动这个圆环
But you can also use your arrow
但我们也可以通过方向键
keys for pixel precise control,
进行精准到像素级别的控制移动
even if you are not zoomed in.
移动之前甚至都不用放大
Also, you notice, all the loops
我们还可以注意到  在所有的
are being synchronized between
渲染目标上  圆环的移动都是
all the render targets.
完全同步的
That helps you to relate values.
可让我们同时查看两边的数值
Let me find an interesting pixel
我们现在就找一个
now.
有趣的像素来看一下
Using a long press will
我们长按  就可以
instantly move the cursor.
立即移动光标
And here we can see something
在这个点上  我们可以看出有些
strange.
奇怪
The depth value inside and
这个颗粒的内部和外部
outside a particle is different,
深度数值不一样
and let's opt, our particles
这很奇怪  正常情况下
shouldn't write into the depths
我们的颗粒不应该写入
buffer, of course.
深度缓冲区
That will be an easy fix.
把这里修好应该很简单
And I'm also sure our new GPU
我相信  我们新的 GPU
debugger will help you fixing
调试工具也可以帮大家快速地
your issues with the GPU.
修好你们 GPU 里的问题
I hope we see each other in the
我希望明天早上可以在实验室里
labs tomorrow morning, or at the
或是在今天的晚些时候
[inaudible] later today.
再次看到大家
Back to my colleague, Seth.
下面还有请我的同事 Seth
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; So now, onto GPU profiling.
好了  下面我们讲 GPU 性能分析
As you know, performance is
我们都知道   对于游戏和其他
crucial to games and other
一些图形应用程序
graphical applications, and
运行性能至关重要
achieving a consistent, fast
我们经常需要能够保持
framework is always necessary.
持续稳定的高帧率
But on the flip side, you want
但另一方面  我们也
to get the most of the GPU for
希望能充分利用 GPU
the best looking game as well,
产出图形效果最好的游戏
and at the same time, increase
而同时希望能够提高效率
efficiency for a longer game
延长高质量的游戏体验
experience.
时间
Well, for all this, you need to
为了做到以上这些  我们就需要
use the GPU Profiling tools.
使用 GPU 性能分析 (Profiling) 工具
The first tool I want to talk
我想讲的第一个工具叫作
about is Metal System Trace.
Metal 系统跟踪 (Metal System Trace)
This is our tool for
这个工具可以
investigating timing issues, by
用来审查计时问题
which I mean investigating cases
我的意思是说  可以审查一些场景
where the CPU and the GPU might
比如有时 CPU 和 GPU 可能
not be running in parallel,
没有在并行运行
because you have some synching
而是因为我们错误地
operations by mistake, and
做了一些同步运行  使得
you're forcing them to work in
CPU GPU 被迫无法并行
serial.
转而连续运行
It's also great for
这个工具还可以
investigating those cases where
用来审查一些场景  比如
you're mostly achieving the
我们大部分的帧都是
framework you want, but
我们想要的样子
occasionally you get a stutter,
但偶尔会有卡顿
and you need to figure out,
然后我们需要去搞明白
okay, what is going wrong in
好了  就在卡顿的那里底
that particular frame?
到有什么问题
It lets you trace your Metal
这个工具可以让我们
workloads through the system,
沿着系统跟踪 Metal 任务
from CPU to GPU to display.
从 CPU 到 GPU 到显示
This year, we've added support
今年  我们还增加了对 VR
for VR applications, with
应用程序的支持
specific VR trace points for
包含具体的 VR 跟踪点
activities like when you query
可针对的活动有比如  当我们向
the head set for post-data, when
虚拟现实头盔查询数据时
you submit your surfaces to the
向 VR Compositor 提交面层
VR compositor, when it does its
的时候  当 Compositor 进行
work to do the compositing, and
排版生成的时候  还有
finally, when it hits the glass
最后显示在头戴设备的
on the headset.
屏幕上的时候
In effect, it lets you trace
事实上  从运动到图像显示
from motion to photon.
整个过程我们都可以追踪
We've also added support this
我们今年还添加了
year for the new ProMotion
对 ProMotion 显示
displays, as you'll find in the
的支持  大家可以在新
new iPads, iPad Pros released
iPad 上找到  就是这周早些时候
early this week, and also
发布的新 iPad Pro  我们还在
support for external GPUs on
macOS 上新增了对外部 GPU 的
macOS.
支持
It is also worth noting there
另外值得注意的  还有
are some great improvements in
我们对工具集也新做了很多
the instruments, to make it much
很棒的改进  让我们可以更加
easier to view other instruments
便捷地查看其他工具集
alongside Metal System Trace in
和 Metal 系统跟踪一起
a more integrated fashion.
比以前整合程度更高了
Our next profiling tool is the
我们另一个性能分析的工具叫作
GPU Shader Profiler.
GPU 着色器分析器 (GPU Shader Profiler)
The tool for probing shader
是分析着色器性能的
performance.
不二选择
It is integrated into the frame
我们把这个工具整合进了
debugger, and lets you view
帧调试工具里  可以让我们
shader time on a per draw call
针对每个绘制指令  每个管道
and per pipeline basis.
分别查看着色时间
And if you're on iOS or tvOS, it
而且  如果在 iOS 或者 Apple tvOS 上
also lets you view it on a per
这个工具还可以让我们分
line basis.
条查看
Well, our first new tool this
我们今年第一个全新的工具
year is designed to work hand in
专门为了与 GPU 着色分析器
hand with the GPU Shader
协同工作而
Profiler.
设计
We call that Metal Pipeline
我们管这个工具叫作 Metal 管道
Statistics.
统计工具 (Metal Pipeline Statistics)
Metal Pipeline Statistics gives
Metal 管道统计工具让我们
you a direct line to the GPU
可以直连 GPU 编译器
compiler to find out about the
编译器根据我们的着色器
quality of the machine code the
生成机器代码  而这个工具可以
compiler is generating from your
让我们查看这些机器代码的质量
shader.
优劣
It gives you a rich set of
这个工具会输出一系列
statistics with things such as
丰富的统计数据  比如
instruction count, instruction
指令数啦  指令混合啦
mix, by which I mean the
也就是说  统计
relative ratio of operations
像比如 ALU 内存  或者控制流
such as ALU or memory or control
这类操作所占的相对比例
flow, and on GPUs where it is
而在那些相关的
relevant, it will also show you
GPU 上  分析输出结果还会
register usage and occupancy.
显示寄存器使用和占用情况
For GPUs such as that, these
对于这部分 GPU 这些
measures are crucial in
统计信息至关重要
understanding what is the
可以帮助我们理解
limitations on how many shaders
同时多少个着色器工作的
can be scheduled simultaneously,
限制条件都是什么
by which shader instances can be
也就是说同时可以排
scheduled simultaneously.
多少个着色场景
But even better are the new
但更好用的  是新的
compiler remarks.
编译器评论功能
With this, the GPU compiler will
有个这个  GPU 编译器就可以
give you direct actual guidance
针对你着色器的运行性能
on the performance of your
给你反馈出直接的  可操作
shader, and things you can do to
的指导  还可以告诉我们具体该改进
avoid performance hits, from
哪里  可以避免性能迟缓
things such as slow math usage,
从比如慢计算使用情况
register spills, and stack
寄存器溢出  和堆栈使用
usage.
情况
It's like having a GPU compiler
这就好像每个 Xcode 都自带了
engineer built into every Xcode.
一位 GPU 编译器工程师
For each remark, it will explain
对于每条评论  下面都会展开解释
what it means, what you can do
到底什么意思  我们可以做什么来
to reduce it, and give you a
提升性能  还会给我们提供一个链接
link to where you need to go to
点击就可以直接定位到需要修改的
fix it.
地方
Well, to demo this new feature,
好了  为了给大家演示这个新功能
I'd like to invite my colleague
我想请我的同事 Jose
Jose to the stage, to give you a
上台  给大家演示一下
tour of Metal Pipeline
Metal 通道
Statistics.
统计工具
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Hello everyone.
&gt;&gt; 大家好
My name is Jose Enrique
我是 Jose Enrique
[inaudible].
我要为大家展示一个新特性
feature of our GPU friendly
那就是我们的对 GPU 友好的
debugger that will have you
调试器 它会助你
produce good quality.
产出高质量的产品
As you can see, we are replaying
大家可以看到 我们
a capture of Metal [inaudible]
正在重放一个在 iOS 上的
demo for iOS.
捕捉 Metal 的演示
The first thing I'm going to do,
我要做的第一件事
I'm going to change my debug
就是把调试导航视图
navigator view from view frame
从按调用检视帧 (view frame
by call to view frame by
by call） 改成按性能检视帧 (view frame by
performance.
performance)
What this gives, what this view
这会给出 这个视图
gives is all these pipelines you
会给出你所捕捉的所有
capture, sorted by time.
通道 按时间分类的
Remember, in Metal, a shader is
记住 在 Metal 里
always linked to a pipeline,
着色器永远连接到通道上
therefore, this is a list of all
因此 这是一个列表
initiator combinations that are
上面是所有
available in [inaudible]
捕捉中可以得到的
capture.
发起程序组合
I am going to go to a
我要看一下
[inaudible] view of the most
最昂贵的通道
expensive pipeline, to see if we
去看看我们是否
can improve the shaders.
能改进着色器
As you can see, this view has
我们可以看到这个视图
three sections.
有三个部分
On top, we have remarks.
最上面的是评价 (remarks)
Remarks are a unique approach to
评价是改进
the compiler shader quality.
编译器着色器质量的好办法
As the report, final compiler
它会报告最终编译器
co-generation issues.
合成时产生的问题
Remember, the GPU will execute
要记住 GPU 会
your shader millions of times
在每一帧中运行着色器上百万次
per frame, therefore, the
因此
[inaudible] you can get, the
你合成的越好
better the performance it will
它的性能就会越好
Remarks also are sorted by
评价还按相关度分类
relevance, and if expanded, they
如果扩张了
offer you reason on why we're
它还会告诉你
reporting it, and our
为什么要上报
recommendation on how to prevent
再给出建议 该如何预防这种情况
it.
发生
Below remarks, we have an
在评价下面
overview for each shader, where
是每个着色器的概况
you can see how the compiler
你可以看到编译器是如何
final assemblies compose
最终组合
[inaudible] of instruction
指令比 (instruction
ratios.
ratio)
And finally, we have a list of
最后 我们还有
all the recalls using this
所用使用这个通道的调回的
pipeline.
列表
This will become very handy
这会在我们
whenever we are iterating over
迭代我们的着色器时
our shaders.
非常方便
So let me showcase an example of
下面让我来展示一个例子
workflow profiler statistics.
是关于工作流剖析数据的
We go to our top remark,
我们来到最上面的评价部分
Register Spill, we can see the
寄存器溢出 (Register Spill) 我们可以看到
compiler is reporting a big
编译器报告了一个很大的
spill, 1,040 bytes.
溢出 有 1040 字节
Spills will cause the GPU to
溢出会导致 GPU
access memory, which can stall
访问内存 这会拖延
your shade execution.
你的着色执行
Knowing that a compiler is
如果能够知道编译器
spilling and fixing it can
发生了溢出 并修复它
drastically improve your shader
这会极大地提升你的着色器
performance, yet finding where
性能 但是要找到
and why the compiler is spilling
编译器在哪里发生溢出
tends to be a time consuming
及其原因 这是一个很耗费时间的
manual [inaudible].
事情
But notice the second and fourth
但要注意的是第二个和第四个
remarks.
评价
Dynamic Stack Store, and Dynamic
动态栈存储 (Dynamic Stack Store)
Stack Load.
和动态栈读取
If expanded, they offer a reason
如果扩展了 它会给出原因
an expensive stack load is
为什么一个昂贵的栈读取
emitted to a dynamic offset in a
在本地数组中被反射到
local array.
动态偏移上
As well as a recommendation, to
同时还会给出建议
reduce the stack access,
减少栈访问
eliminate dynamic access to
消除对于本地数组的
local arrays.
动态访问
This is basically saying that we
这等于在说
have an array variable in our
在我们的着色器代码中
shader code that is storing the
有一个可变数组在
stack and where accessing it
储存栈 而且我们
using some other index variable.
在用一些别的可变索引访问它
This is a very common pattern
这在支持 CPU 时
when providing for the CPU, but
是一个非常常见的模式
GPUs are different, they suffer
但 GPU 不同 我们如果依赖栈的使用
when we rely on stack usage.
就会造成 GPU 的负担
But note the languages below the
但要注意建议下面的
recommendation.
话
It has an exact line number.
它有一个准确的行数
This means that we option click
这意味着我们选择点击它
to it, we'll jump directly to
就会直接跳转到
the [inaudible] line where the
着色器代码行
compiler is actually loading
在这里编译器在从
data from the stack array.
栈数组中读取数据
We just found the compiler
我们找到编译器溢出了
Also these align very well with
同时这与我们的共享性能数据
our shared performing data,
协调得非常好
informing us of the high cost of
会让我们知道这一行的高代价
this line, which now we know
现在我们知道
exactly why.
到底为什么了
The shader is doing two passes.
着色器执行了两个 pass
The first pass, doing some light
第一个 pass 是光线计算
And a second pass, doing the
第二个 pass 是
light accumulation.
光线积累
This speaks to the issue by
这是从 GPU 的角度
working with the compiler but
与编译器共同工作
from a GPU perspective.
来解决问题
The first thing I'm going to do,
我要做的第一件事
I'm going to remove the stack
是移除栈数组
array, I am going to remove it
我要移除它
in relation, and then I'm going
然后我要
to compute the light
第一个循环里
accommodation directly into the
直接计算
first loop.
光线积累
Then I am going to remove the
然后我要移除
second loop, and just not do
第二个循环
that anymore.
不再这样做了
Now, I click my update shader
现在我要点击
button, and wait for the
更新着色器按键 然后
results.
等待结果
What this is going to do, it's
这样做会
going to have the compiler
让编译器进行一次
perform a whole loop
完整的循环优化
optimization and reuse the same
并重新反复使用同样的
reducer over and over, instead
减速器而不是去
of relying on the stack.
依赖那个栈
Once the results are back, we
结果出来之后
can see the instruction ratio
我们就能看到
between the previous and current
前后的合成中的指令比率
[inaudible] has been reduced, as
已经变小了
well as the impact of this
同时 这一更改
change on every single draw call
对通道中用到的每一个绘制调用
used in the pipeline, giving us
的影响也小了
also whole space performance
给了我们整个空间性能
improvements.
的改进
And with this, I conclude my
到这里 关于
example of [inaudible]
这个示例
statistics.
就结束了
I hand it back to my colleague,
交还给我的同事
Seth.
Seth
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Jose.
&gt;&gt; 谢谢 Jose
And finally, onto our last new
下面讲我们今天要介绍的
tool today.
最后一样工具
GPU Counter Profiling.
GPU 计数分析 (GPU Counter Profiling)
As you know, GPU architecture is
大家知道 GPU 构建非常复杂
complex, with a pipeline
因为有由多个可编程
consisting of multiple
的固定功能块组成
programmable and fixed function
的通道
blocks, bottlenecks can occur at
在这个通道中
any point within the pipeline,
任何地方都可能出现瓶颈
and often, at multiple
而且常常是
simultaneous points.
多个地方同时发生
Your job as Metal programmers is
你们作为 Metal 程序员的任务
to minimize fixed function
是让固定功能瓶颈最小化
bottlenecks while efficiently
同时还要有效地
harnessing programmable blocks.
利用可编程块
Well, to do that, our new GPU
要实现这一点 我们的
Counter Profiling is the tool.
新 GPU 计数分析是个好工具
Instead of going directly into
它不会直接去到
the GPU Frame Debugger, it gives
GPU 帧调试器 而是给你
you detailed GPU hardware
详细的 GPU 硬件
performance statistics on a per
性能数据 在 macOS 上
draw call, on macOS and per
以每个 draw call 的频率给出
encoder on iOS and tvOS basis.
在 iOS 和 Apple tvOS 上以每个编码器的频率给出
And instead of giving you an
它不会给你
arcane list of counters that
一个复杂的计数列表
change for every GPU and are
这种列表为每个 GPU 发生变化
hard to understand, and often
难以理解 常常无法
don't tell you what you need to
告诉你你想知道的事
know, we've defined a high level
我们定义了一系列
set of characters that mean the
高等级的字符
same across each GPU.
对每个 GPU 的意义都相同
So you don't have a per GPU
所以你不需要针对每个 GPU 的
learning curve.
学习曲线了
So here is the Counter
这就是计数分析
On the left, we have a graph
在左边是图像视图
view, showing you detailed GPU
显示出详细的 GPU
counter graphs, and on the
计数图 在右边
right, the detail window.
是细节窗口
Let's talk about those in order.
我们一样一样说
In the graph view, we show you
在图像视图中
counters across your frame,
显示了每一帧的计数
where the x axis represents draw
X 轴代表绘制调用
calls, or encoders across time.
或者时间上的编码器
At the top, we show you GPU
在最上面显示的是 GPU 时间
time.
所有的 GPU 计数分析
counter profiling.
都有这个
And then below that, a set of
在它下面
top level counters that
是一系列顶级计数
correspond to the stages in the
对应 GPU 通道中的每个阶段
GPU pipeline, along with some
以及一些其他的
other top level counters that
顶级计数
correspond to shared execution
对应共享执行单元
units, such as the shader core
比如着色器核心
and test units.
和测试单元
For each group, you can drill
你可以在每一组
down to more detailed counters,
深挖到更细节的计数
exploring a lot more data for
在每一个阶段中
each stage, and this is great
探索更多数据
for work flow where you identify
这对那些你认为
it as your first cut, where you
首当其冲可能是
think the performance issue is,
性能发生问题的
and then drill down to see why
工作流很有用 然后你可以看更多细节
it's going on.
从而发现问题
In the detail view, we'll show
在细节视图中
you all the same counters from
我们会向你展示
the counter graph view, but
和计数图像视图中一样的
displayed in full detail
计数 但是会展示全部的细节
numerically.
以数值模拟的方式
And to give it context, we will
为了给它一个背景
show it alongside the median,
我们还会展示出
max, and total values for the
这一帧的中值 最大值
frame as well.
以及总数值
Now, both the graph view and the
图像视图和
detail views support the same
细节视图都支持
full, rich filtering options
全面丰富的过滤选项
that we support elsewhere in the
我们在帧调试器的其他地方也支持
frame debugger, so if you want
这种选项 所以如果你想同时
to just view certain pixel stats
查看某个像素数据
and certain memory stats at the
和某个内存数据
same time, you can put together
你可以把搜索项目合并
the search term, and view
然后依次查看
everything you want alongside
你所需要的所有东西
But I'll highlight the GPU
但我要重点指出
counter profiling is our advance
GPU 计数分析是我们
to bottleneck analysis.
对瓶颈分析的利器
With this, we take all the
我们用它找出
counters that have been pulled
在每一个绘制调用
for each draw call, or each
或者每一个编码器中
encoder, and perform rich
用过的计数
analysis on it, both on a cross
对它进行全面分析
platform basis, and on a per GPU
这种分析是跨平台基础上的
specific basis to identify
也是以每个 GPU 为基础的
potential bottlenecks at each
从而找出每个调用中的潜在瓶颈
Alongside this, we will give you
除了这个 我们还给你
lots of data about, okay, what
很多数据 让你知道
is going on here?
发生了什么
What could cause it?
什么导致的
And then intuitive workflow to
然后是直接导航到
navigate direct to the affected
受影响地区的直观工作流
Now, both the, all the
现在 所有的瓶颈
bottlenecks and all the counters
以及所有的计数
will have rich detailed
都会在 Xcode 文件里
documentation within Xcode docs,
有丰富的细节记录
explaining what each counter
详细解释每一个计数的意义
means in detail, why it might be
为什么它特别高
particularly high or
或者特别低
particularly low, and what you
以及你能
can do about it.
做些什么
To give a demo of this great new
要展示这个
GPU Counter Profiling feature,
很棒的 GPU 计数分析特性
I'd like to invite my colleague,
我想再次请上我的同事
Jose, back to the stage to give
Jose 来给大家做
you a demo of it in action.
实际应用的演示
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Seth.
&gt;&gt; 谢谢 Seth
And hello again everyone.
我又来了
This time, I will demonstrate
这次我要展示的是
GPU counters, a tool that will
GPU 计数器 这个工具
help you analyze your GPU
会帮助你分析
performance.
GPU 的性能
First, I'm going to replay the
首先 我要再播放一遍
same demo that [inaudible] was
刚才放过的演示
on, but this time, we'll focus
但这次 我们要从性能角度
from a performance perspective.
注意观看
The first thing to note is, the
要注意的第一件事是
new GPU gauge, just under the
新的 GPU 测量
FPS gauge.
就在 FPS 测量下面
By clicking on it, we'll
点击它 我们就
navigate to our GP counter view.
来到了 GP 计数视图
As you can see, there is a
我们可以看到
wealth of data here.
这里有很多数据
Available for the first time.
这在之前是没有过的
With this view, you can now
有了这个视图 你们就可以
deliver file any GPU performance
传输文件 在任意捕捉帧中
issue that you have in any of
你所遇到的任何问题
your capture frames.
都可以
So let me demonstrate how to
我来演示一下要怎么
find performance issues.
发现性能问题
First, let's focus on the graph
首先 我们来看图像
view.
视图
As you can see, there is a main
我们看到
spike in GPU time at the very
在一个捕捉的开始
beginning of a capture.
有一个 GPU 时间的高峰
The first thing you want to do
你要做的第一件事
is to zoom in to see a single
就是放大去看单一的回调
recall, there are more
有更多的
offenders.
offender
In order to do that, I can
要做到这一点 我只需
simply pinch and zoom, just like
捏合缩放 这样就
that.
可以了
Any default system behaviors
任何默认系统行为
will work just as you expect
都会按你的意愿
them to.
工作
Now I will see that there is a
现在我会看到这里有一个
main spike.
高峰
You can click on this draw call
你可以通过点击这个
to highlight this impact across
绘制调用
all the pipeline, and hovering
在所有通道中标记这个高峰
over each row will give us
在每一行上悬停会给我们
detailed information on how
细节信息 让我们知道
relevant that stage is for this
它们分别与这个绘制调用
particular draw call.
有多大相关
In this case, Vertex Omission,
在这个示例中 Vertex Omission
Vertex Shader, and Primitives
Vertex Shader 和 Primitives
did not seem to have relevant
似乎都没有相关的
impact.
影响
On the contrary, Fragment Shader
与之相反 Fragment Shader
and Pixels [inaudible] seemed to
和 Pixels Stored 看起来
be quite high.
相当的高
Let's focus on the Fragment
我们先来看一下 Fragment
Shader first.
Shader
If we expand this group we now
如果我们展开这个组
get access to a massive amount
就能够访问大量的
of counter data that gives us
计数数据 这能给我们
detailed information what is
细节信息 让我们知道
going on with the Shader stage.
着色器阶段发生了什么
The last thing that this
最后被计数的
counted, we can quickly see that
我们可以很快看到
the stall time is unusually
延时时间高得出奇
high, over 76%.
超过了 76%
This means that most of the time
这意味着我们花在
we are spending on the Fragment
Fragment Shader 上的
Shader is actually waiting for
大多数时间实际上是在等待
some memory or data to be
一些内存或者数据
This is caused because you are
这是因为你在
fetching from a buffer or from a
从一个缓冲器
texture, but texture captures
或者从一个纹理中取用
should be here in this latency,
但纹理捕捉应该在这个延迟里
so let's go down to our Texture
所以让我们去到纹理单元 (Texture
Unit, to see what is the cache
Unit) 看看缓存率
rate.
是多少
And we can immediately see that
我们可以立即看到
the textures cache rate is also
纹理缓存率也出奇的高
unusually high, almost at 60%.
几乎到了 60%
This means that more than half
这意味着超过一半的
of the texture samples we are
纹理样本
doing are coming from video
都来自视频内存
memory and not from the texture
而不是纹理缓存
Now that we have a better
现在我们对于当前的问题
understanding of the issue at
有了更好的了解
hand, let's focus on the
就来看一看
assistant editor.
辅助编辑器吧
As you can see, the assistant
我们可以看到
editors offer the same graph
辅助编辑器提供了
inform-- counter information as
和图像视图一样的
the graph view was offering, but
计数信息
this time, displayed as a table
这不过这次是以列表视图显示的
But more important, look at the
但更重要的是 看一下顶部
top.
这是我们的瓶颈访问工具
tool.
它会指出我们在
issues that we consider when we
选择的绘制调用内部
analyze all the counters within
分析所有计数时
the selected draw call, and
所考虑到的两个相关问题
point out any relevant issues
并指出了我们认为
that we cconsider important for
值得引起你们注意的
you to pay attention to.
任何相关问题
In this case, highlighting the
在这个示例里
same as we just found manually
标记同样的问题
by checking the graph, that the
也就是我们刚才通过检查图表
texture cache miss rate is high.
手动发现的问题 纹理缓存失误率很高
When expanded, it also offers
展开之后 它还
recommendations on what to
给出了建议 告诉我们应该检查
check.
什么
In this case, check if sampled
在这个示例里 检查
textures have [inaudible], and a
样本纹理是否有纹理映射
quick navigational name to
还有关于这个问题的
relevant views for this issue.
相关视图的快速导航名称
For example, boundary sources,
比如边界资源 (boundary sources)
where we can immediately see
我们可以立即看到
what's the issue at hand, we're
现在的问题是什么
fetching a 4K by 4K RGBA32
我们正在获取一个 4 K 乘 4 K 的 RGBA32
Floating Point Texture with
浮点纹理
[inaudible] in both our vertex
并且这个浮点纹理在 vertex
and our Fragment Shader.
和 Fragment Shader 里都没有纹理映射
This is a 256-megabyte texture
这是一个 256 MB 的纹理
that is fetched all over the
在整个通道里被获取
No wonder we are trashing our
难怪缓存都被浪费了
cache.
想一想我们刚才
just did.
做了什么
This was an incredibly detailed
这是一个非常详细的
view of how GPU internals work.
关于 GPU 内部工作的视图
You finally have the data to
你们终于有了能够证明
prove what [inaudible] telling
从纹理中获取
you, that fetching from the
是昂贵的
textures is expensive, but now
这件事的数据
you know exactly why.
但现在你知道为什么了
Accessing this texture was a
访问这个纹理
star on the Fragment Shader,
在 Fragment Shader 上是一个开始
because it had to fetch some
因为它必须从
data from [inaudible] memory
内置内存中获取数据
that was not available in the
这些数据现在在缓存里
caches.
已经没有了
This level of detail is
这种程度的细节
typically not seen outside
一般在咨询工具之外
consult tools.
很难见到
Solving this issue now is a
解决这个问题现在
matter of balancing performance,
取决于平衡 性能
quality, and correctness, but
质量和正确率
you have demonstrated how you
但你已经展示了
can use GPU counters [inaudible]
要如何运用 GPU 计数和
the GPU Frame Debugger, to help
GPU 帧调试器 来帮助你
you investigate, analyze, and
调查 分析
verify any capture information
分辨任何的捕捉信息
-- any performance information
任何在你的捕捉里的
that you have in your captures.
性能信息
And now, I hand it back to my
现在再请我的同事
colleague, Seth.
Seth 回来
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Jose.
&gt;&gt; 谢谢 Jose
So that is GPU Counter
这就是 GPU 计数
Profiling.
分析
Like all the new features we
和我们今天说过的所有新
talked about today, it's the
特性一样
ultimate joy in Xcode Beta 9,
它是 Xcode Beta 9 里的最大乐趣
and it's available for all Metal
它对所有可以使用 Metal 的
capable GPUs.
GPU 都适用
You will find that more recent
你们会发现
GPUs have more counters
越新的 GPU 就有越多的计数可用
available due to the more modern
因为 GPU 更加现代化了
nature of the GPU, but there's
但所有的 GPU
still a rich and very usable set
都会有丰富可用的
available for all GPUs.
计数
However, we would love to hear
尽管如此 我们还是非常
feedback from you if you feel
期待你们的反馈
there's particular counters that
如果你们觉得哪个计数
were unexposed that would be
还没有 它又非常
particularly valuable, you know,
有价值 那么就请
please drop by the lab, or
务必光临实验室
[inaudible] and we'll be happy
我们会很乐意
to investigate.
进行研究
So what have we talked about
我们今天说了
today?
什么呢
We've talked about some great
我们讲到了
enhancements to the Metal Frame
Metal 帧调试器的一些很好的改进
Debugger, with support for pixel
包括支持像素检查
inspection, inspecting Vertex
检查 Vertex
Shader outputs, rich filtering,
Shader 输出 丰富的过滤
better capture support, better
更好的捕捉支持
capture performance, and Xcode
更好的捕捉性能
Metal Quick Looks.
和 Xcode Metal Quick Look
We've talked about support for
我们还讲到了
debugging and profiling VR
对 Metal 托盘调试器中
applications in Metal Tray
VR 应用的调试和分析的支持
Debugger, and Metal System
以及 Metal 系统托盘
We've talked about Metal
我们讲到了 Metal
Pipeline Statistics, giving you
通道数据
a direct line to the GPU
让你们直接进入
compiler for performance
GPU compiler
information.
获取性能信息
And we've introduced GPU Counter
我们还介绍了 GPU 计数分析
Profiling, giving you unheralded
它让你们能够
access to GPU Performance
访问 Metal 里的
Counter Data in Metal.
GPU 性能计数数据
For more information, check out
更多信息请访问
the website.
网站
Code is 607.
编号是 607
I did want to call out a couple
我还想推荐
of other sessions.
其他的一些演讲
If you didn't catch either the
如果你们没有赶上
Introducing Metal 2, or VR With
Introducing Metal 2 或者 VR With
Metal 2 sessions earlier on this
Metal 2 这两场本周早些时候的
week, it's highly worth going
演讲 它们非常值得
and checking out the video, even
你通过视频来再次观看
if you did see them, it's still
就算你们已经去过
worth checking out the videos.
也请在视频中再次看看它们
And coming up later this
今天下午晚些时候
afternoon, there is a great
还有一场很棒的演讲
session on using Metal 2 for
关于使用 Metal 2 进行计算
Compute, in Grand Ballroom A, at
在 A 大厅
10 past 4.
4 点 10 分开始
And that's it.
就到这里
Thanks for coming.
谢谢大家
Have a great remainder of your
祝你们接下来的
WWDC 17 and enjoy the bash.
WWDC 17 有所收获
Thank you.
谢谢大家